Hello everyone, in this tutorial video, we will learn how to modify a T-shirt into a integrated bunny costume.
First, we need to find stylized under the avatar file in the library window.
Double click on Hana to import this virtual model.
Then we find the garment folder, double click, and then import this T-shirt.
It's the same, double click to open it.
Then press Shift F to open the arrangement point,
click on the sleeve panel, and then click on the arrangement point on the side.
After arranging, we also arrange the front in the corresponding position.
Note that when we arrange, it is placed in the center of the panel to this arrangement point.
So in this way,
when referring to the arrangement point, we should pay attention to the position of the position.
Then we can see that because the sewing line has passed through Hana's hair,
in a relatively small grid like this virtual model hair, it is easy to block the panel.
So we manually move the panel down a little in 3D space,
so that the sewing line will not pass through the hair.
Then press the control key to open the simulation.
Press the control key again to pause the simulation,
then select these two sleeve panels, press the delete key,
and delete them.
Since we are now inserting a male T-shirt,
it does not match Hana's body shape,
so we need to adjust this panel.
The first thing to adjust is its width.
Now we can clearly see that its width is not close to the body.
Then we can use the adjustment panel tool to select the panel on one side of the front and back panels.
No need to select the other side at the same time,
because when we modify this side, the other side will also be modified.
Then drag the side point of the selection box,
and in the process of dragging, press the right key to enter the specific value.
In the input box, we set its width to 80%,
but at this time we will see that the level adjustment next to it is locked.
Now we need to unlock it,
so that we can adjust its width and height separately.
When this pattern is empty,
we can adjust it separately.
Here, we restore its height to 100,
and then click OK.
After opening the simulation,
we will see that this set of clothes is worn on Hana.
Next, we need to adjust the height.
To make it easier to adjust later,
we can put the panel closer to the cutout in the 2D window,
so that we can refer to the cutout to adjust.
Next, we will use the edit panel tool to adjust the panel.
When our lens is switched to the side view,
we will find that its sleeve is relatively large.
Later, we will use these tools in the edit panel tool group to optimize it.
When the mouse clicks on this tool,
click the small scissors to set this menu separately,
so that it is easy for us to select tools.
Next, we can turn on the 3D mirror,
and we can see that the 3D mirror has been selected.
When the 3D mirror is switched to the side view of the virtual model,
we can adjust it according to the effect in the 3D window.
From the edit panel tool,
select the point on the side of the front and back.
When we select a point,
press the Shift key to select other points.
At the same time, select these two points,
and when moving in the vertical direction,
there will be a pink guide line.
During the movement of this guide line,
press the right mouse button to enter the specific vertical.
Here we enter 100 and then click OK.
In this way, the front and back sleeves will be modified at the same time.
Because the rabbit and the wolf costume must be a relatively close-up costume,
so here we need to reduce the surface diameter of the virtual model.
In this way, the air thickness around the virtual model will also be reduced,
and the panel looks a little closer to the human body.
When making tight clothes,
it is best to reduce the surface diameter before adjusting the details.
In this way, we can adjust the surface diameter before adjusting the details.
Another important position is the shoulder line.
The shoulder line determines whether a piece of clothing looks integrated or loose.
For some outerwear, the shoulder line may be out of line.
But for dresses or more tight clothes,
we can refer to the arm movement process.
The arm movement will not change.
In this way, the shoulder line is the part where the shoulder line is located.
So if we want to do a one-piece skirt,
we need to adjust the side of the board.
Now let's go back to the time when there was no arm rotation.
If we are unable to determine how much to adjust,
we can switch to the transparent picture view first,
then we can use the transparent picture as a reference,
Draw some reference lines on the board
If you want to draw reference lines on the costume, you need to use the 3D line drawing function
Find the 3D line drawing tool group in the 3D tool bar
Select the line section 3D board tool in the download menu
Then switch to the transparent picture to show the body of the virtual model
Then click on the shoulder position near the bottom of the page
Then double click on the back piece to finish
This way we can draw a line from the front to the back
Then we switch to the editor board tool
Adjust the board in the 2D window
When we move the point, move it to the vicinity of this gray reference line
Because we are now crossing the front and back
So why is their shoulder line?
Because it's just right
So the back piece also moves to this gray line near it
If you want to edit the 3D line we drew
Or delete this 3D line
You can choose from the download menu
Edit point line 3D board tool
Then we can double click on this line
You can choose the whole line
After selecting, press the delete key to delete
Press Alt 4 to open the transparent picture display
Next, we are going to modify the waist of this skirt
Make it fit more with Hana's body shape
First of all, we need to add a point to the waist
In the case of opening the transparent picture display
Press the number 2 key to go back to the front view
Then click on the back piece to go back to the front view
Then according to this blue dot
Which is the thinnest point of the waist
Use the plus point division function
On the side dot
Click on the position near this blue dot
The shortcut key to the plus point division is X
Then we use the plus point division function
Click on the same position on the back piece
Next, we are going to do a waist reduction effect
First of all, we are going to move this point of the waist inwards
Use the edit tool
In the process of moving
Press the Shift key
You can move in the horizontal direction
Here I moved about 40mm inwards
In the process of adjustment
Pay attention to the front and back pieces
Try to adjust them at the same time
Don't delay the adjustment
The front piece is adjusted too much
So that the curve on the side is not right
And there will be a lot of fish in other places
On the back piece
We will see that its overall shape is not very beautiful
Here we press Ctrl Z
Back to before
Then we use the edit tool
Move point
And hold down Shift
In the process of horizontal or vertical movement
Press the right mouse button
You can enter the specific vertical
Here I choose to make the front waist 30mm inwards
So the back piece
I also enter 30mm in the same way
In the process of horizontal movement
Press the right mouse button
Then double-click to briefly simulate
See the effect
In the process of rotating the view
We will find that this link group
It's not particularly close yet
So we're going to go further
To modify the version
Here we can continue to adjust the point of the waist
Move the point of the front and back waist
Inwards a little bit
In the process of moving
Don't forget to press the right mouse button
You can enter the specific vertical
Here the front and back pieces are inwards
15mm
After opening the simulation and pausing the simulation
We will see that the version
In the cross section of the virtual model
There is already a very obvious neckline of the human body
Even we can see along this fabric
The curve of the human body
In this case
We should no longer
Go to modify the point of the waist
If we are now
Then it will also affect
The effect of our upper body and lower body
Then it may make the lower body
Closer and closer
So we have to change a way
To adjust the version